[wilting]
[growling exhale]
[chittering]
[roaring]
[shrieking]
[Arin grunts]
[Arin] Sorry
hanging out with us
got you into this.
[Euphrasia grunts]
I'm ready
to write this destiny with you,
however it turns out.
[snarling]
[telepathically]
The time... has come.
Thank you, Titanium Ninja.
May our souls meet
in the next cycle.
[Zane] No, not yet!
Trust in Lloyd.
H'yah!
There's fight left in us!
Ah!
Huah!
[monsters snarling]
[whispers echoing]
[gasping]
What was that?
[whispers becoming louder]
[together] Lloyd?
[roaring]
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ So much to see ♪
♪ Jump up, kick back
whip around and spin ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ Whip around and spin ♪
♪ For what's right ♪
[♪♪♪]
Several grid problems
in sectors 7, 9, and 14-Alpha.
[heavy thudding]
[gasping]
[screeching overhead]
Another monster?
We still haven't
finished repairs
from the last attack.
It's... not a monster.
Wrong. It's the worst monster
Imperium has ever known.
[♪♪♪]
[Empress Beatrix]
People of Imperium!
My people!
Who represents you
in my absence?
I am a duly elected official.
Aren't you that boy
who once brought me
a baby dragon?
You dreamt of nothing more
than serving me
as one of my Claws!
That was a long time ago,
when I was brainwashed
by your propaganda,
but I woke up.
All of the people of Imperium
woke up.
We saw who you really are--
a tyrant who lied
about safe energy
while running secret
dragon-draining chambers!
[Beatrix] I drained
those disgusting dragons
to keep my kingdom prosperous.
I hear your "free society"
can barely keep the lights on.
The lives of Imperium Citizens
were perfect
when the rightful ruler
was on her throne!
You lied, and hurt,
and oppressed the people.
Our new Imperium has struggles,
but we work hard
to make our city
function independently,
without harming other beings!
[sighing]
My subjects!
You all once hailed me
as your Good Empress.
Despite your betrayal,
I will give you one chance
to surrender
and receive mercy,
or else I will take Imperium
by force,
and there will be no mercy!
I know where I stand.
Being ruled by tyrants
was the old way,
but it's not about what I want.
We decide
by the voice of the people.
All who wish to open the doors
to Beatrix, speak!
All who wish to stand firm
for the freedom of Imperium
and refuse her,
no matter what
she may throw at us?
[all cheering]
Former Empress,
the people have spoken.
Imperium rejects you.
Again.
Then you choose "no mercy"?
Good.
That's a much more
satisfying option...
for me.
If you step foot
within these walls,
you will be arrested
and prosecuted in a fair trial
for your crimes,
including the death
of your father,
Emperor Levo Vespasian-Orus!
[laughing]
Remember,
despite my better judgment,
I gave you a chance for peace.
What happens next
is on your heads!
Time to rise and shine!
[weapon blasting]
[monsters snarling]
[roaring]
[frightened murmuring]
Our walls can't hold
against all that.
Have we made a mistake?
Ninja!
This is why I kept you alive
in such a humiliating state.
So you can helplessly
witness my triumph.
[groaning]
Now to take back what's mine.
March on Imperium!
[roaring]
[♪♪♪]
[Lloyd] Raah!
[monsters snarling]
[♪♪♪]
I didn't know he could get
all dragony like that.
[Arin] He can't,
or he... couldn't.
[wind gusting]
-[Arin] Look!
-Huh?
Looks like the end
of our destiny
hasn't been written after all!
Ninja... go!
[♪♪♪]
[snarling
[Lloyd] H'yah!
Huh?
How did you stabilize
our powers--
You're a dragon now? How?
-Why--
-Nice tail!
I've always wanted one.
[Lloyd] Slow down.
One at a time.
I already hear so much,
feel so much...
The lean of a tree,
the growth of the grass...
[telepathically]
It is overwhelming at first.
Be patient. Be present.
[breathing deeply]
Your friends' hope
was not false.
The Legend of the Green Ninja
continues in you,
yet the form you've taken...
I've never seen
the likes of it before
in a Green Ninja.
Why would I be the first
to take a new form?
Your life experiences,
your connections...
I feared they would
bring you down,
but perhaps they led you
to unlock
this part of your being.
Ah, my head...
these feelings...
Can I turn them down?
You are connected
to life itself now.
It cannot be turned down,
but you can rise to meet it.
It's... so strange.
Life is strange.
Life is also ordinary.
Life is so many things.
I will miss it.
[groaning softly]
Why aren't they better?
I thought the ritual
would fix everything.
It... it should have,
but I sense...
something out there
manipulating
unbalanced source energy,
draining the Wood,
even though it's distant.
What is it?
A Source Dragon?
Ras?
No.
An artifact, maybe,
or a weapon?
It's more than just a weapon.
It's evil.
To save the Whispering Wood,
I have to stop it.
No.
We have to stop it.
Sign me up,
but how can we find this thing?
Lloyd, can you lead us there?
I just... don't know.
[marching feet]
[♪♪♪]
[grunting with effort]
[rumbling]
[grunting]
[panting]
[rumbling]
Aah!
[groaning]
[weapons powering up]
Sorry, had to.
Wrists were getting
a little sore.
[♪♪♪]
-[Cole] Yaah!
-[Beatrix] How?
[LaRow yelps]
Oof!
That's not for you, whelp!
H'yah!
[Cole] I just need
to touch it once...
[grunting]
[♪♪♪]
Yaah!
[Beatrix] Aah!
Huah! Oh!
[clanging]
[snarling]
[roaring]
[Cole] You've caused Imperium
enough trouble.
Let's wrap this up!
[Beatrix] I will not
be insulted by an outlander!
[monsters roaring]
[Beatrix] Attack!
[Cole] Aah! Yaah!
[rumbling]
Haah! Raah! Yaah!
[grunting]
Ugh, this could not be
more gross!
[Beatrix] A minor distraction.
Scale the wall!
[monsters hissing]
We've gotta get
the Electro-Barrier back up!
You ordered us to shut it down
to conserve energy.
We re-routed
every single power cell.
How could we--?
We find a way!
The Elemental Master of Earth
is risking his life
because he hasn't
given up on us,
so we can't give up either.
Let's go!
H'ah! H'yah!
R'ah!
[car horn plays
"La Cucaracha"]
[engine revving]
[Kai] Ha ha!
Knew if we followed
these masked jerks
we'd find something fun!
[Cole] Jay? Nya? Kai?
[Jay] Get off Cole, you freaks!
Uh, that is Cole, right?
I haven't gotten back
any memories of him
looking like that.
[Nya] I'm, like,
95 to 98% sure that's him.
There she is,
and that must be the weapon
her goons were talking about.
We got here too late.
[Kai] Told ya
you should've let me drive.
[Jay scoffs]
My driving is great!
[tires squealing]
[Kai] Yeah, real great!
[Jay] Better than the time
you melted the Land Bounty's
steering wheel!
[Kai] Can we lose
this guy's memories again?
[Jay] Hold tight!
[tires squealing]
[snarling]
[Nya] Jay, hit the thing!
Now we're talkin'!
[roaring]
[♪♪♪]
[Jay] Whoo-hoo!
Racer Mode was my best idea yet!
[Nya] It was my idea!
[Jay] As the love of your life,
I'm sure I inspired it.
[Nya] You told me repeatedly
not to do it
'cause we'd never use it...
[monster roaring]
...which just made me
want to do it more.
[Jay] Exactly! I'm a master
of reverse inspiration.
Lifting 88A, Side 2,
on your mark.
Mark!
Feed it in.
[powering up]
Yes!
[♪♪♪]
[monsters snarling]
No!
They will not keep me out!
[gasping] Oh no!
Empress, we have several
covert Loyalists still inside.
Looks like
they've sabotaged the barrier.
[Beatrix] When we
take back the kingdom,
remind me to spare them
from my wrath.
[alert tones beeping]
The barrier is turning off!
[Nya] Their barrier failed!
[tires squealing]
[Jay] They probably
could use the help
of the greatest engineer
and inventor
that's basically ever existed.
[Nya] Are you talking about me?
[Jay] Yeah!
Was that not charming enough?
[Nya] You were
a selfish mercenary,
like, three days ago.
Sometimes I'm still not sure
how to take you.
[Jay] That's fair. Now, go!
[tires squealing]
H'yah!
[Cole] Hi!
Didn't expect you.
Last I heard,
you got trapped in a cave.
[Kai] No cave can keep me
from saving your bacon.
What's crackin',
fellow fire people?
Up top!
[monsters snarling]
Leave me hangin'?
Uncool, fire bros!
[snarling]
The fault's not
in the parallel circuits.
[Nya] Percival! Here to help.
Nya!
Oh, man, we could use it.
How did you get
inside the walls?
Waste tunnels.
[inhaling] Still gross.
Beatrix could
send her monsters in that way!
Doubt it.
People like her
never even wonder
how people like us
take out their trash.
What's wrong with the barrier?
We don't know.
We can't find any faults!
I'll check the relays.
[♪♪♪]
[circuits crackling]
[crackling]
[Nya] What?
Sabotage!
[Loyalist]
All hail the Good Empress!
[Nya grunts]
[panting]
[snarling]
[gasping in fright]
[screaming in panic]
[snarling]
[screaming]
[roaring]
[panicked screaming]
[Riyu roars]
[Wyldfyre cheers]
[Frak] Thought we'd never find
where these weirdos were headed.
[Sora] Soon as I heard
the name "Beatrix,"
it was pretty obvious.
[♪♪♪]
[monsters snarling]
[Riyu roars]
[Frak] No offense, but so far,
I'm not loving your hometown.
[Sora] I've never been
a big fan either,
but to be fair,
it had fewer monsters
scaling the walls
when I was a kid.
Ah, it sounds like
it was boring back then.
This rules!
-[engine revving]
-[Sora] Look!
[Cole] Yaah! Yaah!
-Kai!
-[Frak] Cole!
Quit sitting around!
Monster fight!
H'yah! Y'ah! Hi-yah!
[Frak] We're gonna
have to do that too, aren't we?
[Sora] You are.
I'm gonna go see
if I can get
the city's defenses back up.
[Frak] Oh, cool.
Good luck. [gulping nervously]
Whoa!
Oh! Ooh-ho!
Oh!
Wah-ha!
[gasping]
Maybe nobody saw that.
[Jay laughs]
Oh, man, kid!
That was hilarious!
[tires squealing]
Ha ha. Yeah.
Meant to do it.
[Riyu roars]
[Beatrix] The Ninja brought
a repulsive beast against me!
[exasperated sighing]
Please tell me
my dragon-draining facilities
are still intact.
The new senate
dismantled them,
but I should be able
to make them functional again
post haste.
Whoa-ho!
[♪♪♪]
[gasping]
[whirring]
[powering up]
[Nya]
What's that supposed to--?
[panting]
[cutting]
[Nya] No!
Beatrix will be able
to breach the city walls!
[cracking joints]
[Sora] Aah!
[distant screaming]
[Sora] That doesn't sound good.
[device thudding]
[Nya] H'yah!
[Nya] Sora?
Where'd you come from?
[Sora] Long story,
but me, Frak,
Wyldfyre, and Riyu
ended up in a place
with unexpected kittens,
then we jumped
through a fountain
to where Frak's dad was,
but a man in a big hat
made us wear some shame boards.
[Nya]
Maybe I have a concussion,
'cause that sounded like
a bunch of nonsense.
[Sora] It was.
Why are we running?
[Nya] To stop them!
[Nya] Are your powers working?
'Cause we could use them
right now!
[Sora] Wait,
are your powers wonky too?
[Nya] I think everyone's are!
[cutting]
[Sora] Well, worth a shot.
Please work, please work...
[♪♪♪]
Yes!
I think I--
That's not what I was trying--
[Nya] Take the win!
Come on!
[Riyu roars]
[yelping]
[Kai] H'yah!
[snarling]
[Wyldfyre]
Great news, everybody!
Me!
Yee-haw!
[monster snarling]
[Kai] H'yah!
I know you missed me.
[Kai] Well, on a scale
from zero to fire!
Jay and my sister are below zero
on the fun scale!
[Cole] H'ah! H'yah!
[snarling]
H'yah!
[Cole] Frak! Hey, man,
probably not the best time,
but I'm so sorry about
how I acted
when those specters--
[Frak] Forgiven!
There are a lot more kinds
of elemental monsters here
than in Umbrasylvis.
[Cole] Yeah, what--
what's an Umbrasylvis?
[tires squealing]
[♪♪♪]
-[tires squealing]
-[Jay] H'yah!
[screeching]
[tires squealing]
[snarling]
[Jay] Wipers!
Where are the wipers?
[Jay yelps]
[grunting]
[powering up]
[cutting]
[Nya grunts]
[Sora] Yaah!
[Nya] Can you try
to shut it down again?
[Sora] Come on,
one more time...
No!
[slamming]
Oh no!
[Riyu roars weakly]
[Beatrix] Forget that beast!
You must climb the walls!
We cannot be kept out!
[wall segment slamming]
Empress,
your Loyalists inside the walls
have not disappointed.
[Beatrix] They will be thrilled
at my return.
Advance!
[monsters roaring]
[Cole] Waah!
[monsters snarling]
[Cole] Head for that wall--
[grunting]
[monsters roaring]
[Beatrix] Imperium!
I have returned!
[♪♪♪]